# **VOJTECH VRBKA**

Swift Contract Developer

## **CONTACTS**

London, UK
vojtech@vrbka.me
http://vrbka.me
https://linkedin.com/in/vrbka/

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Languages

Swift (6y), Objective-C (3y), SQL(3y), PHP (3y), HTML(3y), JavaScript (2y), Java (1y), Python (1y), NodeJS (1y)

#### **Technologies**

Reactive functional programming, Redux,Reactive feedback, FP, OOP, TDD, BDD, Unit Tests, Integration tests, UI Tests, Snapshot tests, RESTful web services, Core Data, Debugging, Profiling

#### Integrated services and frameworks

Bitrise CI, Swiftlint, fastlane, Fabric (Crashlytics), Firebase, Optimizely, Mixpanel, Instabug, UXCam, Cocoapods, Carthage

**Development software:** Xcode, Git (with gitflow), Sketch

# **EDUCATION**

**2009 - 2014 - Master degree in CS**Technical University of Ostrava, Czech
Republic

2012 - 2013 - ERASMUS program (CS) University of Aveiro, Portugal

# **LANGUAGES**

English (C2), Czech (Native), Portuguese (A2)

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a senior Swift Contract Developer with an MSc in Computer Science and ten years of experience developing successful iOS apps for start-ups and established organisations. I work well in small and big teams (30+ iOS developers) supporting apps with millions of users.

I write clean and reusable code with the right architecture in mind to create elegant and user-friendly solutions. I am proficient in managing and delivering the complete application lifecycle due to my extensive coding background and continuous passion for new technologies.

### **EXPERIENCE**

















#### **Mocha Global**

Remote 08/2020 - now

### Lead iOS Developer (contract)

Mocha does privacy-focused, mobile-first e-commerce. It offers an SDK solution that let you add a custom keyboard to your app and monetise it.

- build two SDKs, from start to finish, including tests, CI, automatic releases
- Tech: FRP, SQLite, Cocoapods, Unit/Integration Tests

#### ClassDojo

San Francisco / Remote 04/2020 - 08/2020

#### Senior iOS Developer (contract)

ClassDojo connects teachers with students and parents to build amazing classroom communities.

- Refactored network layer and implemented tests
- Tech: Core data, PromiseKit, UI/Unit Tests

#### **Babylon Health**

London 10/2019 - 03/2020

### **Senior Swift Developer (contract)**

Babylon believes it is possible to put an accessible and affordable health service in the hands of every person on earth.

- Developed on the door authentication using Auth0
- Tech: ReactiveSwift, ReactiveFeedback, Redux, UI/Unit Tests

## <u>JustEat</u>

London 05/2019 - 09/2019

#### **Senior Swift Developer (contract)**

JustEat is biggest take-away delivery platform in the UK and it's available in 13 more countries.

- · JustEat app redesign, support with app release
- Tech: Unit/UI Tests, CI, Firebase, Optimizely

#### Karhoo

London 06/2018 - 03/2019

#### Senior Swift Developer (contract)

Karhoo is a taxi booking platform integrated with Taxi Fleets worldwide.

- Developed SDK for Karhoo partners and Karhoo Demo App using the SDK
- Tech: VIPER, MVP+C, CI, TDD, Framework development

#### Ostmodern Ltd.

London 04/2018 - 06/2018

#### **Senior Swift Developer (contract)**

Ostmodern is a digital agency specialising in video-centred apps and web.

- · Worked on Olympic Channel and Formula 1
- · Tech: FRP, VOD, UI Tests

2008 - 2018 London / Remote

#### iOS / Web Developer

I worked on many projects over the years, list of all companies and project's I worked on can be found on my Linkedin profile.